<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SFIR | Star Formation/ISM Rendezvous @Princeton</title>
    <description>Star Formation/ISM seminars at Princeton
</description>
    <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://sfirprinceton.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 11:10:54 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 11:10:54 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Entropy Rain and the Solar Convective Conundrum: Dilution and Compression of Individual Convective Downflows</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Large-scale convective flows called giant cells were once thought to transport the Sun’s luminosity in the solar convection zone, but recent observations do not detect giant cells. The absence of giant cells is referred to as the “Solar Convective Conundrum” and calls into question our fundamental understanding of stellar envelope convection. In place of large-scale flows, some authors have suggested the solar luminosity may instead be transported by small droplets of rapidly falling, low entropy fluid. This “entropy rain” could propagate as dense vortex rings, analogous to rising buoyant “thermals” in the Earth’s atmosphere. In this work, we model stellar downflows as dense, negatively buoyant thermals and develop an analytical theory describing their evolution. We verify the theory with 2D cylindrical and 3D cartesian simulations of laminar, axisymmetric thermals in highly stratified atmospheres. Our results show that dense thermals fall in two categories: a stalling regime in which the droplets slow down and expand, and a falling regime in which the droplets accelerate and shrink as they propagate downwards. We estimate that solar downflows are in the falling regime and maintain their entropy perturbation against diffusion until they reach the base of the convection zone. This suggests that entropy rain may be an effective nonlocal mechanism for transporting the solar luminosity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/12/04/sfir-evan-anders.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/12/04/sfir-evan-anders.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>From Superbubbles to the Circumgalactic Medium; How Multiphase Mixing Regulates Galaxy Formation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The flow of gas into and out of galaxies regulates their evolution over cosmic time. The dynamics of these multiphase flows are sensitive to the small scale processes that mediate the mixing of the hot and cold phases. I will highlight two examples where this is mixing is acutely important: (i) the launching of galactic winds by supernova powered superbubbles, and (ii) the balance of turbulent heating and radiative cooling that determines galactic accretion. Then, based on a suite of high resolution simulations, I will present a new model based on the fractal nature of radiative turbulent mixing layers that fully characterizes the physical processes that control the multiphase mixing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/20/sfir-drummond-fielding.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/20/sfir-drummond-fielding.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Numerical Modeling of Star Formation and Feedback in Nuclear Rings</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Nuclear rings are compact ring-like structures often found in central regions of disk galaxies. They are known to be present in 20% of nearby disk galaxies, among which 80% are barred. Nuclear rings in strongly barred galaxies are most likely to be formed by rapid gas infall due to gravitational torque. Considering the fact that the gas is trapped in the nuclear ring and turns into stars, it is important to understand how fast can star formation take place in nuclear rings and how the star formation rate is related to the inflow rate, in order to get a multi-scale view of the black hole feeding process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Star formation in nuclear rings deserves attention on its own. The typical star formation rate is on the order of one solar mass per year, which sometimes comparable to the star formation rate of an entire galaxy. The high star formation rate and the compactness of nuclear rings imply that they are potential sites of pseudobulge formation. At the extremities, they may be able to drive massive outflows energized by supernovae, producing galactic winds that we see today in M82, for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite an importance of star formation and feedback occurring in nuclear rings, detailed investigation has been challenging in both observation and simulation, partly because of its compactness, which requires high observational and/or numerical resolution. To understand how star formation proceeds and how feedback regulates star formation in nuclear ring environment, we have built a numerical testbed especially tailored for nuclear rings. In contrast to global galaxy-scale simulations, our model enables well-controlled experiments to be performed with high resolution, by modeling the bar-driven mass inflow as an input while concentrating only on the nuclear ring region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk, I will introduce nuclear rings in a context of large-scale fueling process, underlining an importance of understanding star formation therein. After describing our model and numerical methods, I will present outcomes of our numerical experiments and discuss the implications, limitations, and future directions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/13/sfir-sanghyuk-moon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/13/sfir-sanghyuk-moon.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The giant molecular cloud lifecycle under the influence of galactic dynamics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The giant molecular cloud (GMC) lifetime places an upper bound on the local time-scale for star-formation, linking cloud- and sub cloud-scale physics to galaxy-scale trends in the star formation rate. Recent observations reveal environmentally-driven trends in GMC properties (e.g. surface densities, velocity dispersions, and turbulent pressures), demanding a systematic, predictive theory of the GMC lifecycle across the parameter space of observable star-forming environments. I will present an analytic theory for GMC lifetimes set by the galactic-dynamical time-scales of the interstellar medium, dependent on just three sets of observables: the rotation curve, surface densities and velocity dispersions of the host galaxy. I will compare and contrast these predictions with a statistical sample of simulated GMCs across three isolated disc galaxies, modelled using the hydrodynamical, moving-mesh code Arepo. My simulations incorporate the features required to accurately model star formation and the influence of stellar feedback on the ISM, including ISM chemistry, a stochastic treatment of star formation, mechanical supernova feedback, and pre-supernova feedback from HII regions. As such, I will (1) examine the nature of the relationship between key GMC properties and the galactic-dynamic environment, and (2) investigate the influence of star formation feedback in truncating the GMC lifetime, relative to the dynamical prediction of the analytic theory. I will also present a comparison of my theoretical results to pioneering observational data currently obtained with ALMA. Together, this combination of analytic, numerical and observational results show that the galactic dynamic environment plays a crucial role in determining GMC lifecycles and thus the star formation rates of their host galaxies.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/06/sarah-jefferson.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/06/sarah-jefferson.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cosmic Ray Transport and the Galaxy Gas Cycle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Despite representing only a billionth of the gas population, cosmic rays have enough energy to significantly shape the structure of the ISM, the supernova-driven outflows that emanate from it, and the surrounding circumgalactic medium (CGM), which contains a large fraction of the baryons in the galactic ecosystem. They exert this influence, however, through micro-scale interactions with plasma fluctuations on scales of order 1 AU. Fully realizing the macroscopic, observable effects of cosmic rays, therefore, requires a truly cross-disciplinary effort between astronomy and plasma physics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will present two recent projects in which I leverage novel numerical techniques and plasma physics-based cosmic ray treatments to simulate cosmic rays in galaxies. This talk will go from small-to-large scales, building in complexity from intuition-building studies of the Parker instability (Heintz, Bustard, and Zweibel 2019) to the role of cosmic rays in the complicated environment of the Magellanic System (Bustard+ 2019, in prep). We find, in each study, that cosmic rays shape their surroundings to promote a flux of gas, magnetic fields, and cosmic rays from disks, develop a cosmic ray dominated halo, and significantly affect the gas phase structure in halos and the CGM. This cosmic ray impact on the galaxy gas cycle promises to narrow gaps between observed and simulated outflows, with the Large Magellanic Cloud being an intriguing, nearby example. Future work to more thoroughly characterize the cosmic ray flux out of the multiphase, turbulent ISM is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/23/sfir-chad-bustard.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/23/sfir-chad-bustard.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Disruption of giant molecular clouds and formation of bound star clusters under the influence of momentum stellar feedback</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Energetic feedback from massive stars plays a pivotal role in shaping the dynamical evolution of giant molecular clouds (GMCs). In this talk, I will present a suite of isolated GMC simulations to investigate how stellar feedback affects the star formation efficiency (SFE) and the subsequent dynamical response of embedded star clusters. We find that the SFE of the clouds scales strongly with the initial cloud surface density and momentum feedback strength. The boundness of the resulting star clusters is a continuously increasing function of SFE. GMCs with efficiency much smaller than 0.5 are still able to form clusters with large bound fractions. The initial density profile of clouds, though has little effect on the SFE, controls the mode of star formation. Clouds with shallower profiles form stars bottom-up, while highly-concentrated clouds form massive star clusters at the center, which gradually accrete mass from the cloud outskirt later. In the end, I will briefly talk about our preliminary results on how dust dynamics enhance the effects of ionizing radiation from massive stars.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/16/sfir-hui-li.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/16/sfir-hui-li.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do Supernovae-driven Hot Outflows Shape the Circumgalactic Medium?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Supernovae (SNe) drive metal-enriched, galaxy-wide outflows. How the 
outflows impact the circumgalactic medium (CGM) depends on (a) how much 
mass/energy/metals the outflows carry, and (b) what is already in the 
CGM. Small-box, high-resolution simulations on SNe feedback constrain 
(a) but leave out (b), whereas cosmological simulations capture (b) but 
use ad hoc models for (a).  We aim at bridging the gap by adopting 
small-box results as the outflow model for galaxy-scale simulations to 
study the resultant CGM. In this talk, I will first summarize the 
recent progress of small-box simulations; particularly, the hot 
outflows appear to be simple yet powerful. Using a Milky Way-mass 
galaxy for an example, we find that, when the star formation surface 
density is low, hot outflows form large-scale fountains in the halo. 
The warm-hot CGM has a universal density profile, which produces the 
observed column density of O VI, VII, and VIII, and X-ray emission. 
Cool gas that condenses out of the hot CGM is highly enriched and 
mainly falls toward the galaxy. In contrast, when the star formation 
surface density is high, the outflows are bipolar in shape and funnel 
metals into the intergalactic medium; cool gas is moderately-enriched, 
with a fraction moving outward at high velocities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/02/sfir-miao-li.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/02/sfir-miao-li.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intensity Mapping Tomography in Broadbands</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The extragalactic background light (EBL) provides a summary statistic 
of cosmological galaxy formation and encodes information from all 
relevant physics in a light-weighted manner. However, one needs to 
resolve key spectral features in the EBL in order to extract the 
physics. For this, we developed a cross-correlation based tomographic 
method to recover previously lost redshift and sub-bandpass frequency 
information for the diffuse light in classic wide-field, broadband 
imaging surveys. I will show the first application with data by probing 
the continuum, Lyα line, and Lyman break in the cosmic UV background 
(UVB) up to z~2 using GALEX All Sky and Medium Imaging Surveys. These 
empirically constrained UVB spectral features provide insights on the 
cosmic star formation history, the absorption due to neutral gas in the 
interstellar medium, and the potential emission from the diffuse 
intergalactic medium. We expect this method to be generically 
applicable over a wide range of wavebands, with a potential of 
performing various spectral diagnostics over the panchromatic EBL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/09/25/sfir-yikuan-chiang.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/09/25/sfir-yikuan-chiang.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Multiwavelength Far-Infrared Polarimetry with HAWC+</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Far-Infrared polarimetry is a useful tool for exploring the role of 
magnetic fields in star formation and Galactic dynamics. The HAWC+/SOFIA 
polarimeter provides a major leap forward in observing capability from 
previous FIR polarimeters by providing both photometric and polarimetric 
imaging at 53, 89, 154, and 214 microns. I will review the instrumental 
capabilities and discuss initial results from HAWC+, including 
multiwavelength measurements of the OMC-1 region.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/06/18/sfir-david-chuss.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/06/18/sfir-david-chuss.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Hall effect in numerical star formation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hall effect is one of the three processes of non-ideal MHD that 
decouple the magnetic field from the gas. By converting poloidal 
magnetic field in toroidal magnetic field, it is especially important 
in star formation because it can either strengthen or weaken the 
magnetic braking, thus influencing the properties of the circumstellar 
disk. I will present my implementation of the Hall effect in the AMR 
code RAMSES, as well as the difficulties we encountered concerning the 
conservation of angular momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/03/13/sfir-pierre-marchand.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/03/13/sfir-pierre-marchand.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
