<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SFIR Princeton</title>
    <description>Star Formation/ISM seminars at Princeton
</description>
    <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://sfirprinceton.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 20:56:48 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 20:56:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>TBA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/06/sfir-sanghyuk-moon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/06/sfir-sanghyuk-moon.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TBA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/23/sfir-chad-bustard.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/23/sfir-chad-bustard.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TBA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/16/sfir-hui-li.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/16/sfir-hui-li.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intensity Mapping Tomography in Broadbands</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The extragalactic background light (EBL) provides a summary statistic 
of cosmological galaxy formation and encodes information from all 
relevant physics in a light-weighted manner. However, one needs to 
resolve key spectral features in the EBL in order to extract the 
physics. For this, we developed a cross-correlation based tomographic 
method to recover previously lost redshift and sub-bandpass frequency 
information for the diffuse light in classic wide-field, broadband 
imaging surveys. I will show the first application with data by probing 
the continuum, Lyα line, and Lyman break in the cosmic UV background 
(UVB) up to z~2 using GALEX All Sky and Medium Imaging Surveys. These 
empirically constrained UVB spectral features provide insights on the 
cosmic star formation history, the absorption due to neutral gas in the 
interstellar medium, and the potential emission from the diffuse 
intergalactic medium. We expect this method to be generically 
applicable over a wide range of wavebands, with a potential of 
performing various spectral diagnostics over the panchromatic EBL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/09/25/sfir-yikuan-chiang.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/09/25/sfir-yikuan-chiang.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Multiwavelength Far-Infrared Polarimetry with HAWC+</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Far-Infrared polarimetry is a useful tool for exploring the role of 
magnetic fields in star formation and Galactic dynamics. The HAWC+/SOFIA 
polarimeter provides a major leap forward in observing capability from 
previous FIR polarimeters by providing both photometric and polarimetric 
imaging at 53, 89, 154, and 214 microns. I will review the instrumental 
capabilities and discuss initial results from HAWC+, including 
multiwavelength measurements of the OMC-1 region.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/06/18/sfir-david-chuss.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/06/18/sfir-david-chuss.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Hall effect in numerical star formation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hall effect is one of the three processes of non-ideal MHD that 
decouple the magnetic field from the gas. By converting poloidal 
magnetic field in toroidal magnetic field, it is especially important 
in star formation because it can either strengthen or weaken the 
magnetic braking, thus influencing the properties of the circumstellar 
disk. I will present my implementation of the Hall effect in the AMR 
code RAMSES, as well as the difficulties we encountered concerning the 
conservation of angular momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/03/13/sfir-pierre-marchand.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/03/13/sfir-pierre-marchand.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Distance to and the Near-infrared Extinction of the Monoceros Supernova Remnant</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on the color indices from the Two Micron All Sky Survey and the 
stellar parameters from the SDSS–DR12/APOGEE and LAMOST spectroscopic 
surveys, the near-infrared extinction law of and the distance to the 
Monoceros SNR are derived together with those of the two nebulae close 
to it, the Rosette Nebula and NGC2264. The distance is found at the 
position of the sharp increase of the interstellar extinction with 
distance, and the nebular extinction is calculated by subtracting the 
foreground interstellar extinction. The distance to the Monoceros SNR 
is determined to be 1.98 kpc, larger than previous values. The color 
excess ratio, EJH/EJKS, is 0.657 for the Monoceros SNR, consistent with 
the average value of 0.652 for the Milky Way. This consistency results 
from the fact that the SNR material is dominated by interstellar dust 
rather than by the supernova ejecta. The dust mass of the SNR is 
estimated as well. The preliminary results on the extinction law of 20 
SNRs will be presented as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/03/13/sfir-biwei-jiang.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/03/13/sfir-biwei-jiang.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Accretion structure of inner protoplanetary disks</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Young stars such as protostars and pre-main-sequence stars grow through 
the interaction with the surrounding disks. To reveal the accretion 
dynamics in the vicinity of the central stars, we have been developing 
a 3D MHD star-disk model using Athena++. We will show the results of 
global 3D MHD simulations of an accretion disk with a rotating, 
magnetized central star. The classical picture predicts that fast 
(~escape velocity) accretion onto the star is possible only when the 
star has a strong magnetosphere. However, we found that fast accretion 
can occur even without the magnetosphere, which seems to be consistent 
with recent observations of Herbig stars that are generally weakly 
magnetized. We are also investigating the origin of violent magnetic 
activity in the protostellar phase, protostellar flares. We will 
briefly discuss a possible occurrence mechanism and a connection to the 
dynamics in black hole accretion disks. Until recently there was only 
one group that succeeded in 3D modeling of accretion onto a central 
star. We will describe how previous pictures will be updated on the 
basis of our results.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/03/06/sfir-shinsuke-takasao.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/03/06/sfir-shinsuke-takasao.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The dynamical effects of radiation pressure on dust in star-forming galaxies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Popular models used in cosmological hydrodynamical simulations of 
galaxy formation have invoked direct radiation pressure on dust as a 
critical component of stellar feedback. I investigate the stability 
properties of direct radiation pressure on dust due to young stellar 
populations within starburst disk galaxies and compute observational 
estimates of galaxy-averaged Eddington ratios. I assess the prospects 
for radiation pressure-driven galactic winds and 
radiation-pressure-driven galactic turbulence and conclude with future 
directions for study of the dynamics of dust, gas, and radiation in 
galaxies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2018/11/28/sfir-ben-wibking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2018/11/28/sfir-ben-wibking.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How stellar feedback and cosmic rays shape galaxies and their halos</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Stellar feedback is an indispensable component in galaxy evolution, 
which regulates star formation, drive galactic winds, and shape the 
galaxy structures. With the “Feedback in Realistic Environment’’ (FIRE) 
simulations, I demonstrate the importance of stellar feedback with a 
few examples: 1. how stellar feedback modifies the underlying dark 
matter halo structures, 2. how stellar feedback produces diffuse dwarf 
galaxies, e.g. ultra diffuse galaxies. In the second part of my talk, I 
will focus on an important kind of stellar feedback — cosmic ray (CR) 
feedback, which we have recently implemented in the code GIZMO and 
coupled to the FIRE stellar feedback model. I will demonstrate its 
strong effects on galaxies, e.g. star formation, galactic wind, and 
circum-galactic medium, but the effects highly depend on the CR 
propagation model. I will then show how to constrain those models by 
comparing our simulations with the observed gamma ray emission. 
Finally, I will discuss the ongoing research and future direction on CR 
feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2018 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2018/11/14/sfir-tsang-keung.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2018/11/14/sfir-tsang-keung.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
