<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SFIR Princeton</title>
    <description>Star Formation/ISM seminars at Princeton
</description>
    <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://sfirprinceton.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 13:41:33 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 13:41:33 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>TBA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/12/04/sfir-evan-anders.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/12/04/sfir-evan-anders.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TBA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/20/sfir-drummond-fielding.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/20/sfir-drummond-fielding.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TBA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/13/sfir-sanghyuk-moon.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/13/sfir-sanghyuk-moon.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TBA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/04/sarah-jefferson.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/11/04/sarah-jefferson.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TBA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/23/sfir-chad-bustard.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/23/sfir-chad-bustard.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TBA</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;TBA&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/16/sfir-hui-li.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/16/sfir-hui-li.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Do Supernovae-driven Hot Outflows Shape the Circumgalactic Medium?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Supernovae (SNe) drive metal-enriched, galaxy-wide outflows. How the 
outflows impact the circumgalactic medium (CGM) depends on (a) how much 
mass/energy/metals the outflows carry, and (b) what is already in the 
CGM. Small-box, high-resolution simulations on SNe feedback constrain 
(a) but leave out (b), whereas cosmological simulations capture (b) but 
use ad hoc models for (a).  We aim at bridging the gap by adopting 
small-box results as the outflow model for galaxy-scale simulations to 
study the resultant CGM. In this talk, I will first summarize the 
recent progress of small-box simulations; particularly, the hot 
outflows appear to be simple yet powerful. Using a Milky Way-mass 
galaxy for an example, we find that, when the star formation surface 
density is low, hot outflows form large-scale fountains in the halo. 
The warm-hot CGM has a universal density profile, which produces the 
observed column density of O VI, VII, and VIII, and X-ray emission. 
Cool gas that condenses out of the hot CGM is highly enriched and 
mainly falls toward the galaxy. In contrast, when the star formation 
surface density is high, the outflows are bipolar in shape and funnel 
metals into the intergalactic medium; cool gas is moderately-enriched, 
with a fraction moving outward at high velocities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/02/sfir-miao-li.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/10/02/sfir-miao-li.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Intensity Mapping Tomography in Broadbands</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The extragalactic background light (EBL) provides a summary statistic 
of cosmological galaxy formation and encodes information from all 
relevant physics in a light-weighted manner. However, one needs to 
resolve key spectral features in the EBL in order to extract the 
physics. For this, we developed a cross-correlation based tomographic 
method to recover previously lost redshift and sub-bandpass frequency 
information for the diffuse light in classic wide-field, broadband 
imaging surveys. I will show the first application with data by probing 
the continuum, Lyα line, and Lyman break in the cosmic UV background 
(UVB) up to z~2 using GALEX All Sky and Medium Imaging Surveys. These 
empirically constrained UVB spectral features provide insights on the 
cosmic star formation history, the absorption due to neutral gas in the 
interstellar medium, and the potential emission from the diffuse 
intergalactic medium. We expect this method to be generically 
applicable over a wide range of wavebands, with a potential of 
performing various spectral diagnostics over the panchromatic EBL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/09/25/sfir-yikuan-chiang.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/09/25/sfir-yikuan-chiang.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Multiwavelength Far-Infrared Polarimetry with HAWC+</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Far-Infrared polarimetry is a useful tool for exploring the role of 
magnetic fields in star formation and Galactic dynamics. The HAWC+/SOFIA 
polarimeter provides a major leap forward in observing capability from 
previous FIR polarimeters by providing both photometric and polarimetric 
imaging at 53, 89, 154, and 214 microns. I will review the instrumental 
capabilities and discuss initial results from HAWC+, including 
multiwavelength measurements of the OMC-1 region.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/06/18/sfir-david-chuss.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/06/18/sfir-david-chuss.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Hall effect in numerical star formation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hall effect is one of the three processes of non-ideal MHD that 
decouple the magnetic field from the gas. By converting poloidal 
magnetic field in toroidal magnetic field, it is especially important 
in star formation because it can either strengthen or weaken the 
magnetic braking, thus influencing the properties of the circumstellar 
disk. I will present my implementation of the Hall effect in the AMR 
code RAMSES, as well as the difficulties we encountered concerning the 
conservation of angular momentum.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/03/13/sfir-pierre-marchand.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://sfirprinceton.github.io//sfir/2019/03/13/sfir-pierre-marchand.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>sfir</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
